You'll like him when he's angry.
The Incredible Hulk is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Louis Leterrier.
Scientist Bruce Banner scours the planet for an antidote to the
unbridled force of rage within him: the Hulk.
But when the military masterminds who dream of exploiting his powers force him back to
civilization, he finds himself coming face to face with a new, deadly foe.
Bruce Banner, played by Edward Norton.
Betty Ross, played by Liv Tyler.
Emil Blonsky, played by Tim Roth.
General 'Thunderbolt' Ross, played by William Hurt.
Samuel Sterns, played by Tim Blake Nelson.
Leonard, played by Ty Burrell.
The Incredible Hulk is a 2008 American superhero film based
on the Marvel Comics character the Hulk.
Produced by Marvel Studios and Valhalla Motion Pictures, and distributed by Universal
Pictures, it is the second film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
It was directed by Louis Leterrier from a screenplay by Zak Penn, and stars Edward Norton as Bruce Banner
alongside Liv Tyler, Tim Roth, William Hurt, Tim Blake Nelson, Ty Burrell, and Christina Cabot.
In the film, Banner becomes the monstrous Hulk as an unwitting pawn in a military
scheme to reinvigorate the "super soldier" program through gamma radiation.
He goes on the run from the military while
attempting to cure himself of the Hulk.
After the mixed reception to Universal's 2003 film Hulk, Marvel Studios reacquired the
rights to the character, though Universal retained distribution rights.
Leterrier, who expressed interest in directing Iron Man (2008) for Marvel, was brought onboard and
Penn wrote a script that was closer to the comics and the 1978–1982 television series.
In April 2007, Norton was hired to portray Banner
and to rewrite Penn's screenplay.
His script positioned the film as a reboot of the series, distancing it
from the 2003 film to give the new version its own identity.
Norton was ultimately not credited for his writing.
Filming took place from July to November 2007, primarily in Toronto, with
additional filming in New York City and Rio de Janeiro.
Over 700 visual effects shots were created in post-production using a
combination of motion capture and computer-generated imagery.
The Incredible Hulk premiered at the Gibson Amphitheatre in Universal City, California, on June 8,
2008, and was released in the United States on June 13, as part of Phase One of the MCU.
It received praise for its action sequences and was considered an improvement
over the 2003 film, but it was criticized as lacking in depth.
The film grossed $265.6 million worldwide.
Norton and Marvel Studios had various production disagreements while working on the film,
including over the final edit, which Marvel Studios deemed uncollaborative.
Norton was replaced in the role of Banner by Mark Ruffalo for
subsequent MCU appearances starting with The Avengers in 2012.
The film explores themes of new york city, rio de
janeiro, superhero, based on comic, fugitive.
The tone is thought_provoking.